http://www.livestrong.org/terms-of-use/privacy-policy

You are here:HomeTerms of UsePrivacy Policy
Donor PolicyThe Livestrong Foundation will not sell, trade or share a donor's personal information with anyone else, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations. The Foundation will only share personal information once the donor has given specific permission to do so.The Donor Bill of Rights was created by the American Association of Fund Raising Counsel (AAFRC), Association for Healthcare Philanthropy (AHP), the Association of Fundraising Professionals (AFP), and the Council for Advancement and Support of Education (CASE). It has been endorsed by numerous organizations—including the Livestrong Foundation—and was adapted for use as a source of information for our donors.	The Donor Bill of RightsPhilanthropy is based on voluntary action for the common good. It is a tradition of giving and sharing that is primary to the quality of life. To ensure that philanthropy merits the respect and trust of the general public, and that donors and prospective donors can have full confidence in the nonprofit organizations and causes they are asked to support, we declare that all donors have these rights: 		To be informed of the organization's mission, of the way the organization intends to use donated resources, and of its capacity to use donations effectively for their intended purposes. 		To be informed of the identity of those serving on the organization's governing board, and to expect the board to exercise prudent judgment in its stewardship responsibilities. 		To have access to the organization's most recent financial statements. 		To be assured their gifts will be used for the purposes for which they were given. 		To receive appropriate acknowledgement and recognition. 		To be assured that information about their donation is handled with respect and with confidentiality to the extent provided by law. 		To expect that all relationships with individuals representing organizations of interest to the donor will be professional in nature. 		To be informed whether those seeking donations are volunteers, employees of the organization or hired solicitors. 		To have the opportunity for their names to be deleted from mailing lists that an organization may intend to share. 		To feel free to ask questions when making a donation and to receive prompt, truthful and forthright answers.
Privacy PolicyThe Livestrong Foundation ("Foundation") has created this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. The following statement explains our information-gathering and dissemination practices for our web sites ("Sites") at:
www.Livestrong.org
blog.Livestrong.org
www.LivestrongattheYMCA.org
www.Livestrongchallenge.org
www.Livestrong5K10k.org
www.TeamLivestrong.org, and
store.livestrong.org.This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically.Throughout this Privacy Policy, "we," "us," and "our" will mean the Foundation. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of persons or entities that the Foundation does not control manage or employ.The Foundation knows that you care how information about you is used. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy.	What information does the Foundation collect from me as an end user?You can browse our Sites without telling us who you are or giving us any personally identifiable information about yourself. When you interact with us through your computer, our Site does record certain non-identifying site usage data, such as the number of hits and visits to our Sites.In order to tailor the information on this Site to your specific needs, you may, at your sole discretion, elect to complete a profile or register with the Foundation in order to purchase products, make donations or participate in events on-line.If you elect to complete a profile or register with the Foundation, you will be asked to provide personally identifiable information that may include among other things your name, address, age, gender, e-mail address, phone-number, fax number, date of birth, whether you are a cancer survivor, type of cancer, phase of survivorship and other healthcare information (collectively referred to as "Profile Information"). Once you provide us with this information you are no longer anonymous to us. We also collect personally identifiable information, such as your user name and password, whenever you login to your account and may in limited circumstances ask you to provide credit card information and other personally identifiable information when purchasing items that are offered for sale or when making a donation. We reserve the right to request any additional information necessary to establish and maintain your account.Some of the programs and activities on our Sites could require the provision of personally identifiable information about you beyond what it is in your Profile Information and you may voluntarily choose to participate in such programs and activities.Our Sites employ "cookies," which are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser. We employ "cookies" to perform three functions: to let us know how long you are logged on to our Sites and to automatically log you out if you are inactive for over thirty minutes; to store your user ID and password so that when you return to our Site you won't have to re-enter some or all of that information; and to provide us with statistics regarding what pages of our Sites you visited, and how long you spent there. You may configure your browser to accept all "cookies," reject all "cookies," or notify you when a "cookie" is sent. However, when accessing an area that requires a password for entry, "cookies" are not optional and continued paths through the password area will not continue if cookies are not enabled.	Information Collected Off-SiteThe Foundation also places advertisements on partner websites and approved third party locations. In addition to collecting data on our Sites, the Foundation is able to obtain personally identifiable information from your voluntary registration through advertising links. The purpose of these ad units is to provide you with a convenient and user-friendly registration option. Registration through off-site links will require the same personal information as the profile completion described previously. The voluntary information you provide is transmitted directly to the Foundation and treated identically to data collected from our own Sites. As noted above, you may customize your browser settings to match your comfort level with regard to the use of cookies on alternate websites.	Does the Foundation track my IP address?When you visit the Sites, our web servers automatically collect limited information about your computer's connection to the Internet, including your IP address (which is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send you data). Your IP address does not identify you personally. We log your IP address to (i) deliver our web pages to you upon request; (ii) tailor our Sites to the interests of our users; (iii) help diagnose problems with our server; (iv) administer our Sites in order to constantly improve the quality of the Sites; (v) measure traffic within our Sites; and (vi) prevent fraudulent use of the Sites by others. The Foundation may also track what we call a Customer Identification Number ("CID"), located within our URL, to determine the web site from which you navigated to get to this Sites. This CID number does not contain personally identifiable information, and the CID number may not be apparent to you. We may also track and analyze non-identifying, aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and users (all of this information is "Aggregated Data").The Foundation does occasionally share your name and address with affiliated organizations with whom the Foundation has a common interest.The Foundation also employs persons and entities to perform functions on our behalf, such as fulfilling merchandise orders, sending mail and email, processing credit card payments or helping with the maintenance or set up of our servers or computers, providing online analytics or assessing web site effectiveness with A/B testing. Such persons or entities have access to your personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but are contractually prohibited from using such information for any other purposes.When you create a profile or register with the Sites, you become a registered user with password access and we use your Profile Information to verify your identity, create your user account, and help us to offer you more personalized features, improve our Sites, and provide you with information that is of the most interest to you. Such Profile Information is also compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis that does not reveal your personal identity and is also considered "Aggregated Data". In addition, you may from time to time be provided with or given the opportunity to obtain additional information of interest, updates, surveys, bulletins or other communications from the Foundation or its partners ("Communications") via e-mail. You may select to opt out of future Communications by following the opt-out provision below.When you join the global movement to fight cancer through our Sites we will use that information to send you email updates. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from the Foundation email list, you may do so by contacting us at livestrong@Livestrong.org with the subject heading "unsubscribe" or by clicking on the link provided in our emails. For more information, please review the section of this Privacy Policy entitled, "Can I opt-out of receiving Communications?".If you choose to make a donation to the Foundation, we will use your credit card information only for this transaction through our secure online payment system. The Foundation does not retain credit card information.If you have provided your telephone number to us through our Site then you may be contacted by one of our volunteers or staff members about urgent campaigns (such volunteers and staff members are bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy and will not use your personally identifiable information for any other purpose).If you send emails through this Site, we will use the personally identifiable information you submit in conjunction with such email as necessary to send the email.	Sending Emails Via the FoundationIn certain cases, we enable you to send individual e-mails to your friends, world leaders or other decision-makers as well as Letters-to-the-Editor to various news publications, through our Site. These messages are sent in your name, with your e-mail address as the return address and your full name and contact information is provided as part of the submission. These messages will only be sent out under your name as you initiate them using our email tool. You are solely responsible for the specific message(s) you send using our email tool. The Foundation takes no responsibility for the content or use of your email address.	How does the Foundation share and disclose my information?Participation in certain programs available on the Sites means that information you provide may be distributed or released publicly. Your participation in these programs is voluntary and you will be notified at the time when your personally identifiable information is collected if your personally identifiable information will be shared.For petitions and surveys you've signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information—for example, we may provide compilations of petitions, with your comments, to world leaders and other targets, or to the press. We will not make your street address publicly available, but we may transmit it to the designated target as part of a petition. This is a standard industry practice in such situations. In no such case will we disclose your email address or phone number, without your permission. We may also make your comments, along with your first name, city and state available to the press and public online. the Foundation is not responsible for the content of use of your email address by campaign targets. 		With your explicit permission, personally identifiable information gathered through our Sites may be shared with the following affiliated groups: 		World leaders, news publications and other targets when you choose to use our email tool to send them messages. 		World leaders, news publications, and the general public when you sign petitions or complete surveys.We may share the Aggregated Data that we collect with business partners, content providers or other third parties to advance goals of research, education, dissemination of information, and the provision of services and support for the treatment of cancer patients.The Foundation has contractual arrangements with certain partners to provide information and services through the Sites. Each of these partners may set and access "cookies" on your computer through the Sites. The use of such "cookies" by each of these partners is subject to their own privacy policy, not the Privacy Policy of the Foundation. We believe these partners share a similar commitment to privacy and urge you to review their privacy policies when visiting their sites. However, we cannot be responsible for their privacy policies.We will also disclose your personally identifiable information if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, regulation or other government authority or to prevent harm to yourself, the Foundation or others. In addition, we may transfer your personally identifiable information to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which the Foundation participates or to a purchaser of all or substantially all of the Foundation's assets.	How does the Foundation protect my Information?The Foundation and/or its subcontractors institute various electronic and administrative safeguards that are reasonably designed to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access, including firewall technologies to help protect your data from hackers and other unwanted visitors. Also, access to the Profile Information contained in your account is protected by use of a password, so you should keep your password private and secure. In the event that we collect your credit card information, we will additionally utilize Secure Sockets Layer Software to encrypt your credit card information you input. Despite use of these safeguards, there are inherent risks in transmission of electronic information. We cannot guarantee and do not represent that your personally identifiable information will always be secure from unauthorized access.We also may use a managed hosting provider and/or other subcontractors to assist us with the provision and maintenance of the Sites. If we do, we will impose on such provider confidentiality obligations for the treatment of information.	Can I opt-out of receiving Communications?To remove your personally identifiable information from our database so that you do not receive further Communications, you can log into your account and change your preferences in your Profile Information. The opportunity to opt-out will be available for at least 30 days after receiving Communication from the Foundation. Requests filed in a timely manner will be processed within 10 days. Please note that under exigent circumstances, we may be required to send you information about the Sites or your account.How can I correct and/or update my data?	You may update and/or correct your Profile Information at any time by logging into your account and then adding and/or deleting any information, as desired or necessary.What about the privacy policies of sites linking to the Sites or to which the Sites link?	We provide links on our Sites to other web sites provided by third parties. In addition, some users access our Sites via another site or a link on another site. We have no control over the sites that link to our Sites or to which our Sites link. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any site other than our Sites. The existence of a link between our Sites and other third party sites does not imply an endorsement of these other sites. We are not responsible for the content of such other sites, nor for the treatment of personally identifiable information might you provide while visiting such other sites.What constitutes my acceptance of this Privacy Policy?	By using the Sites, you expressly consent to the use and disclosure of information as described in this Privacy Policy. The Foundation may modify this Privacy Policy at any time and will post a change notice with the new Privacy Policy on this Site. Your continued use of the Sites after the posting of the change notice to the Privacy Policy will be deemed to be your agreement to the changed terms.Notice to Parents Regarding Participation of Children and Teens.	We want to help you guard your children's privacy. In order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, the Foundation will not knowingly accept "personally identifiable information" from children under the age of thirteen (13) through the Site profile and registration procedures. Our refusal to accept this information does not preclude minors, however, from visiting and using certain features of the Site. In instances where personally identifiable information about children is collected so they can participate in programs offered on the Sites, the rules of this Privacy Policy will apply and the Foundation will obtain verifiable parental consent before knowingly collecting such information from a child under the age of thirteen. Parents will have the option of agreeing to the collection and use of the information and also to the disclosure of such information to third parties. The Foundation will not require a child under the age of thirteen to provide more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation. Parents can review their child's personally identifiable information, ask to have it deleted and refuse to allow any further collection of use of their child's information. A parent wishing to do so should contact the Foundation through the contact information set forth below.	Disclaimer on Information and AdviceThe goal of the Sites is to provide information to cancer survivors and caregivers in an effort to educate them and enable them to more effectively advocate for themselves and participate in making decisions with their healthcare team and other professionals. It is not intended nor should it be construed as providing professional medical, financial or legal advice. The Sites and the information contained on the Sites are not a replacement for obtaining professional medical care or professional legal and financial advice. You should consult a trained medical professional for consultation, diagnosis and treatment of cancer and any topic covered on the Sites. You should consult a trained legal or financial professional for any document covering these topics.The Sites are intended for personal use by individuals coping with and/or recovering from cancer, those supporting friends and loved ones with cancer, and those interested in learning more about topics related to cancer survivorship. You agree not to provide any personally identifiable information of any third party or to create profiles on behalf of any other person unless you are the parent or legal guardian of a child and you create a profile for your child.	Users Outside of the United StatesOur computer systems and some of the computer systems of our third party service providers are currently based in the United States, so your personal data will be processed by us in the United States where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Union. As a visitor from outside the United States, by using the Site you agree to this Privacy Policy and you consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States, which may not offer an equivalent level of protection of that required in the European Union or certain other countries, and to the processing of that information as described in this Privacy Policy.	How do I contact the Foundation?If you suspect that this Privacy Policy has been violated, or if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Sites, or your dealings with the Sites, you may contact us in the following ways:By email: livestrong@Livestrong.orgBy conventional mail:Livestrong Foundation	Attn: Website Privacy Policy	P.O. Box 6070	Austin, TX 78762By telephone: (877) 236.8820
